Toggle navigation [](https://reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/)

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Effective Date: November 17, 2023

1. **PURPOSE AND SCOPE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy explains how Reynolds Consumer Products LLC protects and uses personal information that we collect about you through the websites (“Sites”) where it is posted, including our main website. Reynolds Consumer Products LLC and certain of our Affiliates ("Reynolds") have created this Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. "Affiliates" means any other entity in the Reynolds corporate family that directly or indirectly controls or is controlled by, or is under common control with, Reynolds Consumer Products Inc., including companies such as Reynolds Presto Products LLC that generally do not offer their products and services under a "Reynolds" name brand. By using this website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we treat it. If you do not agree with our Privacy Policy, your choice is not to use our Sites. By interacting with our Sites, you agree to the collection and use of your personal information in accordance with Privacy Policy.

1. **WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**

**Categories Of Personal Information That We Collect**

Personal information is any data that personally identifies, describes, or could be reasonably linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular individual or household (“Personal Information”).

As identified in the chart below, over the past twelve months we have collected or may have collected Personal Information about you when you use our products and services, or interact with us through our Sites and/or call centers operated on our behalf.  

We may share some of this information within our group of companies and with certain third parties for consumer and customer relations, advertising, promotion and insurance purposes. For more information, please see sections IV and V below.  

| **Category of Personal Information Collected by Reynolds** | **Category Collected by Reynolds** | **Category Disclosed by Reynolds** |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Personal Identifiers such as your name, address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, credit card or debit card number, and telephone number. | YES | YES |
| Commercial information including, but not limited to records of products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. | YES | YES |
| Internet or network activity including your browsing history, search history, information on your interaction with our website, application, or advertisement. | YES | NO  |
| Your audio, electronic, visual, or similar information. [https://www.reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/privacy - \_ftn2](https://www.reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/privacy%20-%20_ftn2) | YES | YES |
| Inferences that we may draw from the above information (except for sensitive Personal Information) reflecting your preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes. | YES | NO  |
| Education information, employment, or employment history if you apply for a job through our Sites. | YES | YES |
| Sensitive Personal Information, such as Social Security number, driver’s license number or state identification card number, passport number, bank account information, or other similar identifiers if you apply for a job through our Sites. | YES | YES |

If you purchase products through our Sites, our payment processor will collect financial information, such as credit card or debit card information, to process your payment. 

Reynolds collects and discloses sensitive Personal Information through the Sites only if you apply for a job through our Sites. We do not use sensitive Personal Information for the purpose of inferring characteristics about individuals.

Reynolds does not collect Special Categories of Personal Information about you (e.g., your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). 

1. **How We Use Personal Information**

We use the information we collect about you for a variety of purposes as described in this Policy, including to:

* provide, deliver, maintain and improve the products and services you request;
* provide you with customer service;
* provide updates, upgrades, repairs or troubleshooting our Sites;
* manage and configure our systems and networks;
* understand how the Sites are being used, including through the creation of operational and marketing reports based on de-identified and/or aggregated service usage information;
* inform you of additional products and services that may be of interest to you;
* protect the security of the Sites and our systems, prevent fraud, detect unauthorized reception, use, and abuse of any Reynolds product, service, website or application, and to enforce any Reynolds policy or applicable terms of service;
* protect our rights, our personnel, our property, and the safety of others;
* maintain our accounting, tax and other records;
* comply with applicable federal and state laws and regulations, as well as for the general administration of our business;
* deliver and personalize communications with you;
* create internal business and marketing reports; and
* provide advertising and marketing.  

The legal basis that we rely upon to Process your Personal Information will depend on the circumstances in which it is collected and used. In most cases, the legal basis will fall into one of the following categories where:

* we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you;
* it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests;
* we need to comply with a legal obligation; or
* you consent to the processing of your Personal Information.

You have the right to withdraw such consent at any time by contacting us.

**If You Fail to Provide Personal Information**

Where we need to collect personal information by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have requested from us, but we will notify you if this is the case. 

1. How We Disclose Personal Information
2. Your Personal Information Rights

Reynolds may disclose your Personal Information to any member of our group, which means our affiliates, subsidiaries, and our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries in compliance with applicable privacy principles, laws, regulations and rules.

In order to more efficiently provide the products and services you may request from us, Reynolds may also share your Personal Information with selected third parties who are acting or gathering information on our behalf as our agents, suppliers, or providers.

To this effect, we may disclose Personal Information to the following:

* Entities who perform tasks on our behalf; and
* Entities who agree to provide adequate protections for your Personal Information that are no less protective than those set out in this Privacy Policy; and to use your information only for the purposes for which the third party has been engaged by us.

We may also disclose your Personal Information to third parties if:

* We or any member of our group are involved in a merger, sale, acquisition, or similar transaction, involving all or part of our business or assets, including in connection with due diligence; we may share your Personal Information with the prospective buyer or seller of such businesses or assets.
* We are under a duty to disclose or share your Personal Information in order to comply with any legal obligation, subpoena or other court order; or in order to enforce or apply any of our online Terms and Conditions and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of our group companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction; or for any other reason as required or permitted by law.

Depending on where you are based, you may have certain Personal Information rights. We set these out below:

_Section 1 – Residents of California_ 

**Notice at Collection**

We may collect certain categories of Personal Information about you when you.  Please see [What Personal Information We Collect and How We Use It](#Section2) for a detailed description of the categories of Personal Information, including sensitive Personal Information.  We collect this information to provide the Sites and services to you, as described in more detail in [How We Use Personal Information](#Section3).  We will retain these categories of information as described in more detail in [Data Retention](#Section9).

In the last 12 months, we have collected personal identifiers, commercial information, Internet or other electronic network activity information, audio, electronic, visual or similar information, and inferences drawn from the above.  For job applicants, we also have collected education information and sensitive Personal Information.  We collect this information from you when you provide it to us and when you interact with our Sites and/or call centers.

_Section 2 – Residents of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, and Virginia_

**Your Rights to Know and to Access Personal Information**

If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, or Virginia, and want to know the Personal Information we have collected about you in the last 12 months, you may submit a verifiable consumer request to us, and subject to our verification of that request, we will provide you with the following information:

* the categories of Personal Information we have collected about you;
* the categories of sources from which the Personal Information is collected;
* the business or commercial purpose for collecting, disclosing or selling, if applicable, the personal information;
* the categories of third parties with whom we have shared or sold, if applicable, your personal information; and
* the specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you. 

In addition to these disclosures, you may submit a verifiable consumer request up to two (2) times in a twelve (12)-month period for access to your Personal Information we have collected. When you submit an access request, you can ask us to deliver the information by mail or electronically. **If you elect to receive the information electronically, to the extent it is technically feasible for us to do so, we will provide it in a portable and readily useable format.**

In order to submit a verifiable consumer request, please visit the “How You Can Submit a Verifiable Consumer Request” section below.   

**Your Right to Correct** 

If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Connecticut, or Virginia and you want to correct inaccuracies in the Personal Information that we have collected, processed, or otherwise obtained about you in the last twelve (12) months, you may submit a verifiable consumer request to us, and subject to our verification of that request, we will provide you with the opportunity to correct the inaccuracies, taking into account the purposes of processing the Personal Information.

**Your Right to Delete** 

If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah, or Virginia, and want us to delete the Personal Information we have collected from or about you, you can send us a verifiable consumer request requesting that we delete some or all of such information, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your request to delete, we will delete such Personal Information from our active records, unless an exception applies.  We will also notify any service providers and third parties with whom we have shared your Personal Information of your request. 

Deletion requests are subject to certain limitations. We are not required to delete information where we are permitted or required to retain it, such as for tax, or record keeping purposes, to process orders and transactions, and for solely internal uses consistent with your relationship with us. If we deny your request to delete based on any of these exceptions, we will inform you in writing of the reason.

**How to Submit a Request** 

For us to process a request to know, access, correct, or delete, it is necessary for us to verify your identity.  We will ask you to provide certain additional information about yourself, such as name, physical address, email address and phone number, or other identifying information, to compare to information we have on file for you to verify your identity. We cannot fulfil your request if we cannot verify your identity. It may take up to forty-five (45) days to fulfil your request. If we cannot complete your request within the initial forty-five (45) day period, we will notify you in writing within forty-five (45) days of your initial request. 

To request exercise one or more of your consumer rights, please submit a verifiable consumer request:

* 1-800 433-2244; or
* RCPCommunications@ReynoldsBrands.com

California, Colorado, or Connecticut residents may authorize another person (your “agent”) to submit a request on your behalf. We will also require that you provide us with information sufficient for us to verify that you have authorized this person to act for you and to verify your identity as provided above. 

Residents of Colorado, Connecticut and Virginia can appeal a decision regarding their consumer privacy requests by contacting us by email at [RCPCommunications@ReynoldsBrands.com](mailto:RCPCommunications@ReynoldsBrands.com).

**Your Right to Opt-Out of Selling or Sharing**  

We may disclose certain Personal Information to third parties, including third parties who may process your personal information for targeted advertising. These activities may be considered a “sale” or “share” under these state laws.  The categories of Personal Information we may “sell” or “share” are personal identifiers, commercial information, and Internet or other electronic network activity information.  We may disclose this information to advertising and marketing networks, and data analytics providers. If you are a resident of California, Colorado, Connecticut, Utah or Virginia you have the right to opt-out of sharing your Personal Information with third parties for these purposes.  Email us at [RCPCommunications@ReynoldsBrands.com](mailto:RCPCommunications@ReynoldsBrands.com) with the “Request to Opt-Out” in the message.

**Your Right to Non-Discrimination**

We do not discriminate against consumers for exercising any of their rights with respect to their Personal Information.  If you are a consumer exercising any of your rights under this policy, we will not deny you goods or services; charge you different prices or rates for goods or services; or provide different levels or quality of goods or services to you.

_Section 2 UK and EU data subject rights_

**Your Right to Request Access to Your Personal Information**

If you are a data subject in the UK or the EU, you have the right to submit a data subject access request. This enables you to receive a copy of the personal information we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

We shall take steps to verify any request. This is a security measure to ensure that Personal Information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

You may file more than one requests for access to your Personal Information, but if the number of requests is manifestly excessive, we have the right to refuse to comply. If you elect to receive the information electronically, to the extent it is technically feasible for us to do so, we will provide the requested information in a portable and readily useable format.

We try to respond to all verified requests within one month. Occasionally it could take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

**Your Right to Delete**

You have the right to ask us to delete or remove Personal Information where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your Personal Information where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your Personal Information to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request. 

**Your Right to Correct**

You have the right to request that any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you is corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us. 

**Your Right to Object to the Processing of Your Personal Information**

You have the right to object to the processing of your Personal Information where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party), or where we are processing your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may have compelling legitimate grounds to continue to process your information.

**Your Right to Restrict the Processing of Your Personal Information**

You have the right to ask us to suspend the processing of your Personal Information in the following scenarios: 

* If you want us to establish the data's accuracy.
* Where our use of the data is unlawful, but you do not want us to erase it.
* Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims. 
* You have objected to our use of your data, but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it. 

**Your Right to Request the Transfer of Your Personal Information**

You have the right to request the transfer of your Personal Information. If you make such a request, we will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your Personal Information in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Your Right to Withdraw Consent**

Where we are relying on consent to process your Personal Information you have the right to withdraw this consent at any point. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your Personal Information (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**EU And UK Contact**

We have appointed the Deputy General Counsel, Reynolds Consumer Products, as the individual responsible for the UK and EU aspects of this privacy policy, in particular Reynolds’ compliance with the GDPR. If you are a UK or EU data subject, and you have any questions about this privacy policy or if you wish to exercise any of your data subject rights, please use the following contact details: RCP Privacy, Reynolds Consumer Products, 1900 West Field Court, Lake Forest, Illinois 60045, Attention: Law Department, or by email at [RCPLegalTeam@reynoldsbrands.com](mailto:RCPLegalTeam@reynoldsbrands.com).

1. **International Transfers for Individuals Outside the United States**

If you are based outside the US, we share your Personal Information with Reynolds business units/affiliates/subsidiaries. This will involve transferring your data outside the country or region where you are located. Whenever we transfer your Personal Information to the US, we will take reasonable steps to protect it, including by using contractual safeguards, such as standard contractual clauses, obtaining your consent, or using other lawful means to transfer the information. 

1. **Security and Data Integrity**

We take measures to ensure that your Personal Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Once we have received your information, we will use reasonable procedures and security safeguards to protect it from unauthorized access. Unfortunately, however, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its security and any transmission is at your own risk.

1. **Cookie Notice**

In order to improve our Sites, we use “cookies” to maintain a record of your visit. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your device when you visit one of our Sites. Cookies help us to improve our Sites and to enable us to understand how users interact with the Site; to store information about your preferences; to speed up your searches and may be used to recognize your computer. You can find more information at www.allaboutcookies.org and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. If you would prefer to prevent your computer from accepting our cookies, you may follow your Internet browser’s steps for doing so. Please note, however, that if you do disable cookies from your browser, you may not be able to access certain sections of our websites.

We use both persistent cookies and session cookies.  Persistent cookies remain on your device and allow websites to remember your preferences and recognize you when you return to the Sites. Session cookies allow websites to remember your actions on the Sites during a visit, and are automatically removed from your device when you close your browser. 

We use the following types of cookies:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Cookie Type** | **Purpose** |
| **Strictly necessary/ Technical** | These cookies are necessary to allow us to operate our Sites so you may access them as you have requested. These cookies, for example, let us identify the IP address from which you access Site content. |
| **Analytical /Performance** | These cookies are used by us or our business partners to analyze how our Sites are used and how they are performing. For example, these cookies track what pages are most frequently visited, and from what locations our visitors come from. These cookies include, for example, Google Analytics cookies.  In accordance with our Privacy Policy, the Firm will not share any personally identifiable information about you with third parties except as otherwise noted above. |
| **Functional** | These cookies let us operate our Sites and Services in accordance with the choices you make. These cookies permit us to "remember" you in-between visits. |
| **Marketing** | These cookies are used by us or our partners to market our products and services to you based on your activities on our Site or purchase history with us. |

To administer our Sites and for research purposes, Reynolds also works with third party service providers to track and analyze usage and volume statistical information from our Site users. These third party service providers use persistent cookies to help us to improve the user experience, manage our Site content, and track user behavior.

The specific cookies that we use for our Sites are as follows:

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Cookie Type** | **Description** | **Duration** | **Type** |
| **\_ga** | The \_ga cookie, installed by Google Analytics, calculates visitor, session and campaign data and also keeps track of site usage for the site's analytics report. The cookie stores information anonymously and assigns a randomly generated number to recognize unique visitors. | 2 years | Analytics |
| **\_gid** | Installed by Google Analytics, \_gid cookie stores information on how visitors use a website, while also creating an analytics report of the website's performance. Some of the data that are collected include the number of visitors, their source, and the pages they visit anonymously. | 1 day | Analytics |
| **\_gcl\_au** | This cookie is installed by Google Tag Manager to collect data and provide analytics about how visitors interact with our advertising campaigns. | 3 months | Analytics |
| **\_gat** | This cookie and variations on it are installed by Google Universal Analytics to restrain request rate and thus limit the collection of data on high traffic sites; the variations also allow us to monitor visitor interaction with our websites and site performance. | 1 minute | Performance |
| **\_aeaid** | This cookie is installed by AudioEye to support the functioning of the accessibility features. | 1 year | Functional |
| **test\_cookie** | This cookie is set by Doubleclick to enable us to service advertising consistent with your interests. | 15 minutes | Advertising and Analytics |

How to manage cookies

You can prevent most cookies from being set onto your device by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. You can also adjust the setting of your Internet browser to reject the setting of all or some cookies and to alert you when a cookie is placed on your device. Please note that if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including strictly necessary cookies) you may not be able to access or use all or parts or functionalities of our Sites and Services.

For more information on cookies and how you can manage them on your browser and device, please see [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) if you are located in Europe or [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) if in the United States.

**Changes to our cookie notice**

Any changes to our cookie notice will be posted on our Sites.

1. **Data Retention**

We will only retain your Personal Information for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. We may retain your Personal Information for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a likelihood of litigation.  When determining the appropriate data retention period, we consider the amount and nature of Personal Information, the purposes for which we collected it and whether we can achieve those through other means, and applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting, and other requirements. 

In some circumstances we will de-identify your Personal Information so that it can no longer be associated with you. This Privacy Policy does not apply to such de-identified information. 

1. **Children**

We offer a range of Sites to our users, but our Sites are not intended to target children. We do not knowingly request or collect Personal Information from children. If we learn that we have collected information from a child, we will delete that information as provided under applicable privacy law. From time to time, we may offer Sites that appeal to a large range of people, and we may provide separate or additional Site-specific privacy notices consistent with applicable laws. As used in this Policy, “children” and “child,” refer to children under the age of 13, except for those jurisdictions where the privacy law specifies a different age. 

1. **Other Sites**

Our Sites may contain links to other websites, including the websites of third parties who are acting on our behalf as our agents, suppliers, or providers.

Reynolds is not responsible for the content, security, or privacy practices employed by third party websites. Once you leave our website, we encourage you to review the privacy policy of any website linked to from one of our Sites before using it.

1. **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is current as of the effective date set forth above. Reynolds reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time consistent with applicable privacy laws and principles. If we make a material change to the way we collect or use your information, we will inform you of those changes.  We encourage you to check this page regularly for updates.

1. **Complaints and Questions**

Reynolds takes your privacy concerns seriously. If you have any complaints regarding this policy, or questions about our privacy practices, you may write to [RCPCommunications@ReynoldsBrands.com](mailto:RCPCommunications@ReynoldsBrands.com) or send a letter to RCP Privacy Complaints at Reynolds Consumer Products, 1900 West Field Court, Lake Forest, Illinois 60045, Attention: Law Department.

You have the right to complain to your relevant data protection authority if you are not satisfied by our response. 

This agreement outlines the terms of use for any website (the “Website”) operated by Reynolds Consumer Products LLC, a Delaware corporation located at 1900 West Field Court, Lake Forest, IL 60045 ("Reynolds", "we", "our", or "us"). Our websites, which are linked to this policy, and marked © Reynolds Consumer Products LLC, enable users of the Internet ("you" or "your") to view and learn more about us or our products.

1\. Use. Please read these terms of use (the "Agreement") carefully before accessing the Website. By accessing the Website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions set forth in the Agreement. If you do not wish to be bound by the Agreement, you are not authorized to use the Website. Reynolds reserves the right to modify the Agreement at any time. You agree to review the Agreement periodically to be aware of any such modifications. You further agree that your continued use of the Website shall be deemed to be your conclusive acceptance of the current version of the Agreement. We will indicate that changes to the Agreement have been made by updating the date indicated after "Last Modified" at the end of the Agreement with the date on which such changes were made. A current version of the Agreement is accessible via the footer of the Website's homepage.

2\. Copyright. All content contained on the Website, including but not limited to video, clips, photographs, text, graphics, logos, icons, images and software (collectively, "Content"), is the property of Reynolds or its licensors and is protected by U.S. and/or international copyright laws. Any reproduction, modification, distribution, transmission, republication, display or performance of the Content contained on this Website is strictly prohibited. If you use material appearing on the Website in violation of this Agreement, you may be liable for infringement, misappropriation or other causes of action to the fullest extent of the law.

3\. Trademarks. Unless otherwise indicated, all names, graphics, designs, logos, page headers, button icons, scripts, commercial markings, trade dress, and service names included in the Website are trademarks of Reynolds or its licensors or suppliers (collectively, the "Trademarks") and are protected by the trademark laws of the United States and other jurisdictions. You may not use, copy, reproduce, republish, distribute, modify or post any Trademarks in any way, including in advertising or publicity pertaining to or distribution of materials on the Website, without our prior written consent. The Trademarks may not be used in any manner that is likely to cause confusion, or that disparages or discredits us.

4\. Employment. You acknowledge and a0gree that you will only submit your resume or other materials to us in order to apply for a position if you are at least eighteen (18) years of age and are eligible to work legally in the United States.

5\. Links. Reynolds and/or third parties may provide links to other websites of possible interest to you. Because we have no control over such websites, you acknowledge and agree that we are not responsible for the availability of such websites and do not endorse and are not responsible or liable for any content, advertising, services, products, or other materials on or available from such websites. You also acknowledge and agree that Reynolds shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with the use of or reliance on any content, advertising, services, products, or other materials on or available from such websites. All such websites shall be subject to the policies and procedures of the owner of such websites.

6\. DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES.

6.1 YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THE WEBSITE IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK. REYNOLDS DOES NOT MAKE ANY REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY: (i) AS TO THE ACCURACY, CORRECTNESS, COMPLETENESS OR USEFULNESS OF ANY CONTENT APPEARING ON THE WEBSITE AND IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY ERRORS OR OMISSIONS IN ANY CONTENT APPEARING ON THE WEBSITE, OR (ii) CONCERNING THE ACCURACY, RELIABILITY, OR QUALITY OF ANY CONTENT OR PRODUCTS APPEARING ON THE WEBSITE. THE WEBSITE AND ANY PRODUCTS APPEARING ON THE WEBSITE ARE PROVIDED TO YOU "AS IS" AND REYNOLDS MAKES NO REPRESENTATION OR WARRANTY OF ANY KIND TO YOU, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED. SPECIFICALLY, REYNOLDS DISCLAIMS ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, MERCHANTABILITY, AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. 6.2 YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES WILL REYNOLDS BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOSS OR DAMAGE CAUSED BY YOUR RELIANCE ON CONTENT OBTAINED THROUGH THE WEBSITE OR CAUSED BY YOUR CONDUCT. REYNOLDS DOES NOT GUARANTEE CONTINUOUS, UNINTERRUPTED OR SECURE ACCESS TO THE WEBSITE, AND THE OPERATION OF THE WEBSITE MAY BE INTERFERED WITH BY NUMEROUS FACTORS OUTSIDE OF OUR CONTROL. REYNOLDS IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY FAILURES, DELAYS OR INTERRUPTIONS OF THE WEBSITE.

7\. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY.

7.1 IN NO EVENT SHALL REYNOLDS BE LIABLE FOR ANY INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENCIAL OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH YOUR USE OF THE WEBSITE INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, FOR LOST PROFITS OR BUSINESS, OR ANTICIPATED LOST PROFITS OR BUSINESS, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBLITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. REYNOLDS'S AGGREGATE LIABILITY TO YOU OR ANY THIRD PARTY IN ANY CIRCUMSTANCE IS LIMITED TO ONE THOUSAND DOLLARS ($1,000).

7.2 SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF CERTAIN WARRANTIES OR THE LIMITATION OR EXCLUSION OF LIABILITY FOR INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENCIAL OR PUNITIVE DAMAGES. ACCORDINGLY, SOME OF THE ABOVE LIMITATIONS IN SECTIONS 6 OR 7 HEREOF MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.

8\. Indemnification. You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold harmless Reynolds from any claim, expense or demand including, without limitation, for reasonable attorneys' fees, made by any third party due to or arising out of your breach of this Agreement, or your violation of any law or the rights of a third party.

9\. Privacy. Reynolds is committed to safeguarding your privacy. The terms regulating the handling of personally identifiable and other information in connection with the Website is described in our [Privacy Policy](https://www.reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/privacy).

10\. Governing Law. You acknowledge and agree that this Agreement shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the internal laws of the State of Illinois, excluding conflict of laws provisions thereof that would indicate the application of the laws of any other jurisdiction and you hereby submit to exclusive jurisdiction in the federal and state courts of Illinois. You agree to receive service of process through certified mail or by other means sanctioned by law, and you expressly waive any claim of improper venue and any claim that such courts are an inconvenient forum.

11\. General. If any provision of this Agreement is held to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be struck and the remaining provisions shall be enforceable. You agree that this Agreement may be assigned by Reynolds, in its sole discretion, to a third party. Section headings are for reference purposes only and in no way define, limit, construe or describe the scope or extent of such section. Our failure to act with respect to a breach by you or others does not waive our right to act thereafter with respect to that or any subsequent or similar breaches. This Agreement sets forth the entire understanding and agreement between us with respect to the subject matter hereof. The provisions of this Agreement will survive termination or expiration to the extent necessary to carry out the intentions of the parties.

12\. Contact Us. If you have any questions or concerns regarding the Website, please [Contact Us](https://www.reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/contact) or write to us at Reynolds Consumer Products, 1900 West Field Court, Lake Forest, IL 60045, Attn: Communications.

[REYNOLDS CONSUMER PRODUCTS STATEMENT OF ETHICS, BUSINESS PRINCIPLES AND CODE OF CONDUCT](#collapse-accordion-29-3)

[Click here](https://www.reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/sites/default/files/2023-04/Statement%20of%20Business%20Principles%20and%20Code%20of%20Conduct%20Policy.pdf) for full statement.

[Click here](https://www.reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/sites/default/files/2023-06/Statement%20of%20Business%20Principles%20and%20Code%20of%20Conduct%20Policy%20%28Spanish%29.pdf) for full statement (Spanish.)

[REYNOLDS CONSUMER PRODUCTS POLICY ON SOCIAL ACCOUNTABILITY AND ETHICAL TREATMENT](#collapse-accordion-29-4)

Reynolds Consumer Products LLC promotes business practices and policies that show respect for the value of all human beings. It requires that its suppliers do so as well. All Reynolds and supplier locations shall provide a safe working environment to all employees, which includes proper training, appropriate equipment to safely perform the job, and a clean environment where safe behavior is emphasized.

All Reynolds Consumer Products and supplier locations shall also maintain conditions of employment where all workers are free to choose employment, where there is no forced, bonded, or involuntary labor, and where there is no use of child labor. There shall be no discrimination in hiring, compensation, access to training, promotion, termination or retirement based on age, gender, race, color, caste, national origin, disability, religion or veteran status.

Regardless of culture, community, or country, Reynolds Consumer Products will not use any supplier that is involved in or associated with human trafficking, bonded labor, involuntary servitude, use of child labor or sexual slavery. Reynolds Consumer Products maintains a diligent supplier control program specifically evaluating its suppliers and validating their compliance with these standards. In the event any supplier audit finds evidence that the supplier is in violation of Reynolds Consumer Products Social Accountability and Ethical Treatment Policy, the supplier relationship will be terminated or suspended until such time as the supplier comes into full compliance.

Should you discover that this policy is in violation, we ask you to report it to us immediately by using our [Contact Us form](https://reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/contact).

[REYNOLDS CONSUMER PRODUCTS COMMITMENT TO SUPPLY CHAIN SECURITY AND CUSTOMS TRADE PARTNERSHIP AGAINST TERRORISM (CTPAT)](#collapse-accordion-29-5)

Reynolds Consumer Products LLC and Reynolds Presto Products Inc., and all their affiliates through their directors, officers, employees and agents (collectively, Reynolds,) are firmly committed to full and complete compliance with all laws enforeced by the US Bureau of Customs and Border Protection and all US Government Agencies, including, but not limited to, all US laws prohibiting the importation of any merchandise mined, produced or manufactured wholly or in part by convict, forced, indentured or child labor. We also commit to protecting our supply chains from criminal activies such as drug trafficking, terrorism, human smuggling, and illegal contraband.

Reynolds is committed to meeting the standard of reasonable care mandated by the Customs Modernization Act of 1993. To this end, Reynolds is committed to the continuing development of a comprehensive compliance program which identifies legal requirements under the United States Customs laws applicable to Reynolds' importing activities. This program will inform applicable personnel as to thes requirements, establish procedure and policies to ensure integrity and consistency in the execution of import operations, institue internal control measures, and require interdepartmental cooperation in meeting compliance program initiatives.

Additionally, as a participant of the Customs Trade Partnership Against Terrorism (CTPAT) program, Reynolds commits to working diligently in concert with its vendors and their factories, forwarders, consolidators, customs brokers, carriers, and any other releveant service provider to establish controls related to cargo security initiatives.

This policy and the ongoing development of a comprehensive compliance program will receive and will continue to receive the full support of Reynolds' executive management.

Reynolds has a long-standing Corporate Compliance Program for the purpose of establishing and maintaining processes to prevent and detect violations of law. Additionally, Reynols operates under a Code of Business Conduct and Ethics. [https://reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/ethics](https://reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/ethics)

Any question regarding the implementation or administration of this policy should be directed Stephanie Sherrod, Customs Compliance Manager, or to the General Counsel, David Watson. 

[Click here](https://www.reynoldsconsumerproducts.com/sites/default/files/2024-09/Patents%20List%209-30-2024.pdf) for full list.

[REYNOLDS CONSUMER PRODUCTS DOES NOT ACCEPT UNSOLICITED PRODUCT IDEAS](#collapse-accordion-29-7)

Reynolds Consumer Products, LLC (“RCP” or “Reynolds”) does not accept unsolicited product or ideas from the public.  Reynolds Consumer Products Is not responsible to review or respond to ideas submitted through any channel. Ideas submitted in any format (mail, email, social media, telephone) will not be reviewed. Physical items, including mail, will be returned without review.  

The Company will continue to research new product ideas using internal and other contracted resources. The Company will continue to use U.S. and International patent filings to research existing product ideas and protections and adhere to all laws in the countries where we do business.

As employees and contractors of the Company are hired expressly to aid and benefit our business, all product ideas generated are the sole property of Reynolds Consumer Products. The company names individual employees as authors or contributors to patents.

Copyright© 2024 Reynolds Consumer Products
